原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
前情提要
翻译    草草  Silmar  煮粥达人  泰斯
翻译     盐湖凉开水  妖精希亚  山猫
校对     泰斯·雪诺  Silmar
时间轴     加森  格瑞塔  Toozii
战争结束了  凛冬已至
The war is over. Winter has come.
战争没有结束
The war is not over.
真正的敌人不会等暴风雪过去
The true enemy won't wait out the storm.
顾问     屈畅(ccxx)
北境之王  北境之王
The King in the North! The King in the North!
后期     吉吉·波顿 拉图
总监     泰斯·雪诺
我们的叔叔攸伦失踪很久后回来了
Our uncle Euron returned home after a long absence.
人人影视Pro
■
人人影视官方唯一APP
在线观看，离线缓存，百度云
■
他杀死了我们的父亲
He murdered our father,
夺走了雅拉的盐王座
and took the Salt Throne from Yara.
app.YYeTs.com
官方网站下载 : 人人影视Pro
如果我们不走  他还会杀死我们
He would have murdered us if we'd stayed.
为我造千艘战舰  我将还你们整个世界
Build me a thousand ships, and I will give you this world.
暴风雨要来了
There's a storm coming.
你们今晚得找个屋子避雨
You'll be wanting a roof tonight.
我没多少钱
I don't have much,
但我藏了点银子  没被强盗抢去
but I have hidden a bit of silver from the bandits.
你干了什么
What did you do?!
冬天一到  他们都得死
They'll both be dead come winter.
北方已有冷风吹起
Cold winds are rising in the North.
我们需要好手帮忙
We need good men to help us.
你救下的人会远比你伤害过的多  克里冈
You can still help a lot more than you've harmed, Clegane.
现在回头为时不晚
It's not too late for you.
送我去旧镇
Send me to Oldtown.
我来成为新学士
I'm to be the new maester.
学城有世界上最大的图书馆
The Citadel has the world's greatest library.
我会学习知识  到时候用得上的
I'll learn about things that all help when...
那些东西来的时候
when they come.
阿多  快点
Hodor, hurry!
你确定自己准备好了吗
Are you sure you're ready for this?
我现在是三眼乌鸦了  我必须准备好
I'm the three-eyed raven now. I have to be ready for this.
知道是谁下令雕绘这桌子的吗  戴佛斯爵士
Do you know who had this table carved and painted, Ser Davos?
伊耿·坦格利安
Aegon Targaryen.
伊耿曾经住在这里
Aegon used to live here,
是坦格利安家族建造了这座城堡
and the Targaryens built this castle.
是的  是他们建的
Aye. So they did.
我想和你一起回家  可我们的家早给人夺走了
I want us both to go home. But they took it from us.
我们怎么回家啊
How do we go home?
您已身处局中
You're in the great game now,
此局凶险骇人  您害怕吗
and the great game's terrifying. Are you afraid?
我的名字叫艾莉亚·史塔克  我要你知道
My name is Arya Stark. I want you to know that.
你们在想  我为什么把你们都召来
You're wondering why I brought you all here.
毕竟  我们刚举办过盛宴
After all, we just had a feast.
老瓦德怎么会
Since when does old Walder
两周不到  就举办两次盛宴
give us two feasts in a single fortnight?
统领着三河流域
Well, it's no good being Lord of the Riverlands
要是不能跟家人庆祝还有何用
if you can't celebrate with your family.
这是我的想法
That's what I say!
说得好
Yes!
我叫齐了所有算个玩意的佛雷
I've gathered every Frey who means a damn thing
好告诉你们我对我们伟大家族的打算
so I can tell you my plans for this great house
因为凛冬已至
now that winter has come.
但首先  祝酒一杯
But first, a toast!
再不要喝多恩的马尿
No more of that Dornish horse piss!
这是最好的青亭岛金色葡萄酒
This is the finest Arbor gold!
英雄当饮美酒
Proper wine for proper heroes!
并肩作战
Stand together!
你不许喝
Not you.
好酒不能浪费在娘们身上
I'm not wasting good wine on a damn woman.
我或许不够可亲可爱
Maybe I'm not the most pleasant man.
我承认  但我为你们骄傲
I'll admit it. But I'm proud of you lot.
你们是我的家人  红色婚礼上
You're my family, the men who helped me
是你们帮我屠杀史塔克家族
slaughter the Starks at the Red Wedding.
没错
Yes, yes.
干杯
Cheer.
你们都是勇士
Brave men, all of you.
残酷地杀死一个怀孕的女人
Butchered a woman pregnant with her babe.
割了一个五个孩子的母亲的喉咙
Cut the throat of a mother of five.
屠杀了你们请进家门的宾客
Slaughtered your guests after inviting them into your home.
但你们没把史塔克家的人杀尽
But you didn't slaughter every one of the Starks.
这是个错误
No, no, that was your mistake.
你们应该斩草除根  一个不留
You should have ripped them all out, root and stem.
留下一头狼活命
Leave one wolf alive
羊群永远不得安宁
and the sheep are never safe.
等有人问起发生了什么
When people ask you what happened here...
就说北境永不遗忘
tell them the North remembers.
告诉他们佛雷家凛冬已至
Tell them winter came for House Frey.
权力的游戏 第七季 第一集
你们是野人
You wildlings?
我是梅拉·黎德  霍兰·黎德之女
I'm Meera Reed, daughter of Howland Reed.
这是布兰登·史塔克
This is Brandon Stark,
奈德·史塔克之子
son of Ned Stark.
我怎么知道你说的是真的
How do I know that's true?
你去过先民拳峰
You were at the Fist of the First Men.
你去过艰难屯
You were at Hardhome.
你见过死人军团
You've seen the Army of the Dead.
你见过夜王
You've seen the Night King.
他就要来找我们了
He's coming for us.
我们所有人
For all of us.
好  进来
Okay, come on.
带他们进去
Let's get them inside.
我要所有北境学士搜寻文献
I want every northern maester to scour their records
查出任何关于龙晶的记载
for any mention of dragonglass.
龙晶能杀异鬼
Dragonglass kills white walkers.
现在它对我们比黄金更宝贵
It's more valuable to us now than gold.
我们得找到它  我们得开采它
We need to find it, we need to mine it,
我们得拿它做武器
we need to make weapons from it.
所有十到六十岁间的人
Everyone aged 10 to 60
要每天用矛  枪  弓和箭练武
will drill daily with spears, pikes, bow and arrow.
也该教教夏天生的男孩怎么打仗了
It's about time we taught these boys of summer how to fight.
不仅是男孩
Not just the boys.
我们若想保卫北境
We can't defend the North
就不能只靠一半人口去打仗
if only half the population is fighting.
你要我让孙女手拿长矛吗
You expect me to put a spear in my granddaughter's hand?
男人为我打仗时  我可不打算在火边做针线
I don't plan on knitting by the fire while men fight for me.
我虽小  葛洛佛大人  我虽是个女孩
I might be small, Lord Glover, and I might be a girl,
但我跟你一样是北境人
but I am every bit as much a Northerner as you.
是的  小姐  没人质疑...
Indeed you are, my lady. No one has questioned--
我保卫北境  不需要你允许
And I don't need your permission to defend the North.
我们会开始训练
We'll begin training every man,
熊岛的每一个男女老幼
woman, boy, and girl on Bear Island.
说得好
Aye!
准备抵御强敌的同时
While we're preparing for attack,
我们还需要加固防御
we need to shore up our defenses.
我们和死人军团之间
The only thing standing
唯有一座绝境长城
between us and the Army of the Dead is the Wall,
而长城几百年来一直驻守人数不足
and the Wall hasn't been properly manned in centuries.
我不是自由民的国王
I'm not the king of the Free Folk.
但如果我们想一起熬过这个冬天...
But if we're going to survive this winter together...
你要我们为你驻守要塞
You want us to man the castles for you?
没错
Aye.
我们上次见到夜王是在艰难屯
Last time we saw the Night King was at Hardhome.
距艰难屯最近的要塞是东海望
The closest castle to Hardhome is Eastwatch-by-the-Sea.
那我就去那里
Then that's where I'll go.
看来我们成了守夜人了
Looks like we're the Night's Watch now.
如果他们突破长城
If they breach the Wall,
首当其冲的两座城堡
the first two castles in their path
是最后壁炉城和卡霍城
are Last Hearth and Karhold.
安柏家和卡史塔克家背叛了北境
The Umbers and the Karstarks betrayed the North.
他们的城堡该被夷为平地
Their castles should be torn down
一块石头也不留
with not a stone left standing.
城堡又未犯罪
The castles committed no crimes.
要迎接大战  我们需要每一座堡垒
And we need every fortress we have for the war to come.
最后壁炉城和卡霍城应该分给新的家族
We should give the Last Hearth and Karhold to new families,
支持过我们对抗拉姆斯的家族
loyal families who supported us against Ramsay.
对
Aye!
安柏家和卡史塔克家
The Umbers and the Karstarks
跟史塔克家并肩战斗了数百年
have fought beside the Starks for centuries.
世代忠心耿耿
They've kept faith for generation after generation.
但他们背弃了誓言
And then they broke faith.
我不会为几个不肖子孙所犯之罪
I'm not going to strip these families of their ancestral homes
将这些家族逐出祖居的城堡
because of the crimes of a few reckless sons.
那么叛者不罚
So there's no punishment for treason
忠者无赏吗
and no reward for loyalty?
背叛的惩罚是死亡
The punishment for treason is death.
小琼恩·安柏死在战场上
Smalljon Umber died on the field of battle.
哈拉德·卡史塔克死在战场上
Harald Karstark died on the field of battle.
他们是为拉姆斯效命战死
They died fighting for Ramsay.
将城堡赏给
Give the castles to the families
为你效命战死之人的家族
of the men who died fighting for you.
我担任守夜人军团总司令的时候
When I was Lord Commander of the Night's Watch...
处死过背叛我的人
I executed men who betrayed me.
处死过抗命不遵的人
I executed men who refused to follow orders.
我父亲过去常说
My father always said,
"判人死刑者必须亲自动手"
"The man who passes the sentence should swing the sword,"
我也一直遵循他的教诲
and I have tried to live by those words.
但我不会为父亲的罪过责罚儿子
But I will not punish a son for his father's sins,
我也不会剥夺一个家族
and I will not take a family home
经营了数百年的家园
away from a family it has belonged to for centuries.
这就是我的决定
That is my decision,
最终决定
and my decision is final.
奈德·安柏
Ned Umber.
亚丽·卡史塔克
Alys Karstark.
几百年来  我们的家族
For centuries, our families fought
在战场上并肩战斗
side by side on the battlefield.
我请求你们再次对史塔克家宣誓效忠
I ask you to pledge your loyalty once again to House Stark,
做我们家族的封臣
to serve as our bannermen
听凭调遣  有求必应
and come to our aid whenever called upon.
请起
Stand.
昨日的战争已不再重要
Yesterday's wars don't matter anymore.
北境必须团结一心
The North needs to band together,
每一个活着的北境人
all the living north.
你们会站在我身边吗  奈德  亚丽
Will you stand beside me, Ned and Alys,
从今开始  直到永远
now and always?
Now and always!
你是我妹妹  但我现在是国王
You are my sister, but I am king now.
你会开始戴王冠吗
Will you start wearing a crown?
你在那些领主和夫人面前
When you question my decisions
质疑我的决定  会有损我的威信
in front of the other lords and ladies, you undermine me.
我都不能质疑你的决定了吗
So I can't question your decisions anymore?
你当然可以  但是...
Of course you can, but--
乔佛里从不允许任何人质疑他的权威
Joffrey never let anyone question his authority.
你认为他是个好国王吗
You think he was a good king?
你认为我是乔佛里吗
Do you think I'm Joffrey?
你跟乔佛里完全不同
You're as far from Joffrey as anyone I've ever met.
谢谢
Thank you.
你很擅长这种事
You're good at this, you know.
-擅长什么  -统治
- At what? - At ruling.
才怪
No.
是真的
You are.
真的
他们尊重你  真的尊重你
They respect you, they really do,
但是你必须...
but you have to
你笑什么
Why are you laughing?
父亲过去怎么说的
What did father used to say?
"但是"才是重点  前面都是狗屁
Everything before the word "But" is horse shit.
他从没对我说过这话
He never said that to me.
当然没有  他从不在女儿面前说粗话
No. No, he never cursed in front of his girls.
因为他想保护我们
Because he was trying to protect us.
他从不想让我们看到这世界有多肮脏
He never wanted us to see how dirty the world really is,
但是父亲保护不了我  你也不能
but Father couldn't protect me and neither can you.
-别总想着保护我  -好  我不会了
- Stop trying. - All right, I'll stop trying to protect you
你也不要再破坏我的威信
and you stop trying to undermine me.
我没有破坏你的威信
I'm not trying to undermine you!
你必须比父亲精明
You have to be smarter than Father.
你需要比罗柏精明
You need to be smarter than Robb.
我爱他们  我想念他们
I loved them, I miss them,
但是他们犯了愚蠢的错误
but they made stupid mistakes,
害得他们掉了脑袋
and they both lost their heads for it.
我怎么才能更精明
And how should I be smarter?
听你的话吗
By listening to you?
听我的话有这么可怕吗
Would that be so terrible?
君临来的信鸦  陛下
A raven from King's Landing, Your Grace.
"兰尼斯特家族的瑟曦一世
"Cersei of House Lannister, First of Her Name,
安达尔人和先民的女王
Queen of the Andals and the First Men,
七国守护..."
Protector of the Seven Kingdoms--"
她要怎样
What does she want?
前往君临
Come to King's Landing.
屈膝认罪  不然就接受叛徒的命运
Bend the knee or suffer the fate of all traitors.
你太过专注北方的敌人
You've been so consumed with the enemy to the north,
忘记了南方的威胁
you've forgotten about the one to the south.
我专注对付夜王是因为我见过他
I'm consumed with the Night King because I've seen him.
相信我  你若也见过  就不会考虑别的
And believe me, you'd think of little else if you had, too.
面对夜王  我们还有长城可守
We still have a wall between us and the Night King.
我们与瑟曦之间毫无阻隔
There's nothing between us and Cersei.
我们跟瑟曦相隔数千里之遥
There's a thousand miles between us and Cersei.
凛冬已至  兰尼斯特的手下是南方军队
Winter is here. The Lannisters are a southern army.
他们的势力从未触及这么北的地方
They've never ranged this far north.
你懂军事  但是我了解她
You're the military man, but I know her.
对敌人  她不毁灭绝不罢休
If you're her enemy, she'll never stop until she's destroyed you.
每一个惹过她的人  都被她设法除掉了
Everyone who's ever crossed her, she's found a way to murder.
听起来你好像很佩服她
You almost sound as if you admire her.
我从她身上学到很多
I learned a great deal from her.
这是什么
What is this?
这是我们一生的期待
It's what we've been waiting for our whole lives.
这就是父亲训练我们的目的  不管他是否知道
It's what Father trained us for, whether he knew it or not.
他知道
He knew it.
逼我记住每一个该死的城镇
Made me memorize every damn city, town,
湖泊  森林与山脉
lake, forest, and mountain.
现在都是我们的了  我们只消伸手去拿
It's ours now. We just have to take it.
你自从回来后就不大说话
You've been quiet since you came home.
你在生我的气吗
Are you angry with me?
不  没有生气
No, not angry.
你害怕我吗
Are you afraid of me?
我应该怕你吗
Should I be?
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安任命提利昂为首相
Daenerys Targaryen has chosen Tyrion to be her Hand.
此时此刻  他们正在渡过狭海
Right now, they're sailing across the Narrow Sea,
志在夺回她父亲的王座
hoping to take back her father's throne.
我们的弟弟
Our little brother,
那个你最爱的弟弟
the one you love so much,
那个你放走的弟弟
the one you set free,
那个杀死父亲  杀死我们长子的弟弟
the one who murdered our father and our first-born son,
正在我们的敌人身旁  为之出谋划策
now he stands beside our enemies and gives them counsel.
他带着一支强大的舰队
He's out there somewhere at the head of an armada.
他们会在哪里登陆
Where will they land?
龙石岛
Dragonstone.
那里有可供舰队停泊的深水港
They have deep-water ports for the ships.
史坦尼斯走后城堡无人占领
Stannis left the castle unoccupied,
而且那里还是她出生之地
and that's where she was born.
东边的敌人
Enemies to the east.
南边的敌人
Enemies to the south--
艾拉莉亚·沙德和她的那群小婊子
Ellaria Sand and her brood of bitches.
多恩海
西边的敌人
Enemies to the west--
奥莲娜  那个老贱人
Olenna, the old cunt.
另一个叛徒
Another traitor.
高庭
北边的敌人
Enemies to the north.
奈德·史塔克的私生子当上了北境之王
Ned Stark's bastard has been named King in the North
还有那个杀人的婊子珊莎在他身边
and that murdering whore Sansa stands beside him.
到处都是敌人  我们被叛徒包围了
Enemies everywhere. We're surrounded by traitors.
你现在掌管着兰尼斯特的军队
You're in command of the Lannister army now.
-我们该如何进军  -凛冬已至
- How do we proceed? - Winter is here.
如果我们喂不饱自己的人马就打不赢这场战争
We can't win a war if we can't feed our men and our horses.
提利尔家手里有粮食和牲畜
The Tyrells have the grain, the Tyrells have the livestock.
提利尔家的封臣会与
Will the Tyrell bannermen stand alongside
多斯拉克部落和奴隶士兵无垢者共事吗
a Dothraki horde and Unsullied slave soldiers?
如果他们认为丹妮莉丝会获胜的话
If they think Daenerys will win.
没人愿意为失败的一方而战
No one wants to fight on the losing side.
现在  我们看起来必败无疑
Right now, we look like the losing side.
我是七国女王
I'm the Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
顶多有三国
Three kingdoms, at best.
我不清楚你是否明白我们现在的处境有多危险
I'm not sure you understand how much danger we're in.
我明白我们正面临生死之战
I understand we're in a war for survival.
我明白败者必死
I understand whoever loses dies.
我明白胜者会建立
I understand whoever wins could launch a dynasty
一个延续千秋万代的王朝
that lasts a thousand years.
谁的王朝
A dynasty for whom?
我们的孩子都死了
Our children are dead.
只剩下你我了
We're the last of us.
那就是你我的王朝
A dynasty for us, then.
我们从没谈过托曼的事
We never talked about Tommen.
没什么可谈的
There's nothing to say.
我们的小儿子自杀了
Our baby boy killed himself.
他背叛了我
He betrayed me.
他背叛了我们俩
He betrayed us both.
我们要整天悼念逝去之人吗
Should we spend our days mourning the dead--
母亲  父亲  还有我们所有的孩子
mother, father, and all our children?
-瑟曦  -我爱他们  我爱过
- Cersei-- - I loved them. I did.
但是他们已成灰烬  而你我还活着
But they're ashes now and we're still flesh and blood.
我们是最后的兰尼斯特  余者都不重要了
We're the last Lannisters, the last ones who count.
即使是兰尼斯特  没有盟友也无法生存
Even Lannisters can't survive without allies.
我们的盟友在哪里
Where are our allies now?
你看到瓦德·佛雷和他家族的下场了
You saw what happened to Walder Frey and his family.
我听说了
I heard.
-我们怎能信任那样一个人  -是不能
- How could we ever trust a man like that? - We couldn't.
他是个没用的老懦夫
He was a useless, old coward,
但是佛雷家支持过我们
but the Freys supported us.
现在他们都死了
Now they're all dead.
杀他们的人必定是敌非友
Whoever killed them is no friend of ours.
我们需要盟友
We need allies.
更强大  更有价值的盟友
Stronger, better allies.
我们单枪匹马赢不了这场战争
We can't win this war alone.
你以为我听了父亲四十年的教导
You think I listened to Father for 40 years
什么都没学到吗
and learned nothing?
葛雷乔伊
The Greyjoys?
你邀请葛雷乔伊家来君临
You invited the Greyjoys to King's Landing?
-不是他们所有人  -可看起来是这样
- Not all of them. - Well, it looks like all of them.
我邀请了攸伦·葛雷乔伊
I invited Euron Greyjoy,
铁群岛的新王
the new King of the Iron Islands.
你自己说的  我们需要更强大更有价值的盟友
You said yourself we needed stronger, better allies.
-就是他们  -他们怎么是更有价值的盟友
- There you are. - How are they better allies?
他们跟佛雷家有什么区别
How are they different from the Freys?
他们同样违背了誓言
They both broke their promises
一旦有利可图便谋害了昔日盟友
and murdered their former friends as soon as it suited them.
每个人一旦有利可图都会这么做
So does everyone when it suits them.
跟佛雷家不同的是  他们有船
Unlike the Freys, they have ships.
-而且擅长杀戮  -他们一无所长
- And they're good at killing. - They're not good at anything.
我了解铁民  他们身材矮小  暴戾无常
I know the ironborn. They're bitter, angry little people.
他们只懂得劫掠
All they know how to do is
自己造不出和种不活的东西
steal things they can't build or grow themselves.
攸伦·葛雷乔伊不是为劫掠而来
Euron Greyjoy didn't come here for that.
那他为了什么
Oh, what did he come here for, then?
一位女王
A queen.
我刚被选为铁群岛之王
The moment I was chosen Lord of the Iron Islands,
他们就背叛了我
they turned on me.
他们的亲叔叔
Their own uncle.
他们偷了我最好的几艘船  跑了
They stole my best ships and ran.
乘着它们漂洋过海
Sailed them right across the world
将其献给了龙女王
and gave them to the Dragon Queen
使她得以率军渡海  攻击你们
so she could bring her armies here to attack you.
据我所知  跟您的遭遇比起来
It's nothing compared to the treason you suffered
我那点众叛亲离算不上什么
at the hands of a family member, from what I hear.
但我还是很恼火
But still, it bothers me.
杀了他们能让我好过很多
Murdering them would make me feel a lot better.
而且既然那些背叛我们的家人
And since it appears that all our treasonous family members
现在都是一伙的
are fighting for the same side,
我想我们两位正统的君主
I thought we rightful monarchs
应该联合起来剿灭他们
could murder them together.
你不是什么正统的君主吧
You're not a rightful monarch, though, are you?
葛雷乔伊家族曾起兵叛乱
The Greyjoys rebelled against
妄图自立为王
the throne for the right to be monarchs,
但据我所知  你们败得很惨
but as I recall, you were soundly defeated.
说到这个
Come to mention it,
你不就是那个挑起叛乱
weren't you the one who started that rebellion
把船开到凯岩城  烧了兰尼斯特舰队的人吗
by sailing to Casterly Rock and burning the Lannister fleet?
确实打了我们一个措手不及
You certainly caught us there.
在你而言可谓一步好棋
Very smart move on your part.
当然  我们还是攻克了铁群岛
Of course, we all made it to the Iron Islands anyway.
我当时在场
I was there.
我记得很清楚
I remember very well.
我看到你了
I saw you.
我听过很多传言
I heard so much talk.
绝世无双  无人能敌
The best in the world. No one can stop him.
老实说  我先前还不信
I didn't believe it, to be honest.
但我必须承认  当你破墙而入
But I must say when you rushed through the breach
大杀四方...
and started cutting people down...
的确荡人心魄
it was glorious.
像一场舞蹈
Like a dance.
我杀的可是你的亲族
The people I was cutting down were your own kin.
反正那地方人太多
The place was getting crowded.
我观赏得非常愉快  真的
I enjoyed watching it. I truly did.
我也喜欢杀葛雷乔伊家的人
And I enjoyed killing Greyjoys.
对我来说是好事
A good thing for me.
要不是你击溃我们  我也不会走上逃亡之路
If you hadn't crushed us, I wouldn't have gone into exile.
我要是不走
If I hadn't done that,
就不会成为十四海之内最强大的船长
I wouldn't be the greatest captain on the 14 seas.
但不是最谦逊的
If not the most humble.
您也不谦逊
You're not humble.
您是广阔国度的女王
You're the queen of a great nation.
您才不稀罕铁群岛
You don't care about the Iron Islands.
那里有的不过是石头  鸟粪...
They're nothing but rocks and bird shit and--
和一帮无趣至极的人
and a lot of very unattractive people.
然而铁舰队
The Iron Fleet, on the other hand,
就是另一回事了
that's something else entirely.
它是维斯特洛有史以来最强的舰队
It's the greatest armada Westeros has ever seen.
有了铁舰队  您就拥有了海洋
With the Iron Fleet, you own the seas.
您可以打败东方的侵略者
You can defeat the invaders of the east
也可铲除南北方的伪王
and the pretenders of the north and south.
条件是什么
What do you want in return?
我还是个小男孩时
Ever since I was a little boy,
就希望长大以后
I wanted to grow up and marry
娶世上最美的女人为妻
the most beautiful woman in the world.
所以我来了
So here I am,
带来一千艘船
with a thousand ships
和我健全的双手
and two good hands.
我拒绝你的求婚
I decline your proposal.
为什么
Why?
你不值得信任
You're not trustworthy.
你曾背弃盟友
You've broken promises to allies before
一有机会就杀了他们
and murdered them at the nearest opportunity.
你还杀了你的亲兄弟
You murdered your own brother.
您也应该试试  感觉好极了
You should try it. Feels wonderful.
我不指望您立刻相信我
I don't expect you to trust me outright.
您需要我自证忠诚可靠
You need proof of my honest intentions.
以我的经验
In my experience,
赢得女人心最好的办法就是送礼物
the surest way to a woman's heart is with a gift.
一份无价的礼物
A priceless gift.
不为您拿到那份礼物
I won't return to King's Landing
我决不回君临
until I have that for you.
威兰德学士
Ah, Maester Weyland.
典型的酒鬼肝脏
A drinker's liver if ever I saw one.
称一下
Weigh that.
一时欢愉的胜利
The triumph of transitory pleasures.
人类的诅咒
Mankind's curse.
博士  我在想...
Archmaester, I was wondering...
多重
What's the weight?
Um, 147.
不知道您有没有考虑过我的提议
I was wondering if you had considered my proposition.
我不记得你有什么提议
I don't remember your proposition.
我问过您  鉴于我在北境所见
I asked you if, in light of what I've seen in the North,
能不能允许我进入图书馆的禁区
if I could have access to the restricted area of the library.
禁区是学士们专用的
That area is reserved for maesters.
-你是学士吗  -不是
- Are you a maester? - No.
你的提议不太有说服力  不是吗
Not a very strong proposition, is it?
博士  无意冒犯
Archmaester, with respect,
我见过他们
I've seen them...
死人军团
the Army of the Dead.
异鬼
The white walkers.
我是被派来学习怎么打败他们的
I was sent here to learn how to defeat them,
但学城的所有人
but everyone in the Citadel,
起码是愿意和我说话的人
those who will even talk to me,
他们全都质疑异鬼的存在
they all doubt the walkers ever existed in the first place.
学城的所有人质疑所有事情
Everyone in the Citadel doubts everything.
这是他们的本分
It's their job.
但是长夜的故事不可能全是编的
But the tales of the Long Night can't be pure fabrication.
互不关联的资料里有太多相似的记载
Too many similarities from unconnected sources.
禁区里的资料吗
Sources in the restricted area?
正是
The very same.
你这么执念于异鬼一事
And the simplest explanation
最简单的解释就是
for your grating obsession with the white walkers
你在说实话
is that you're telling the truth
如你所说  你确实见过
and that you saw what you say you saw.
所以您相信我
So, you believe me.
是的
I do.
你还不去称那颗心脏
You'll finish weighing that heart?
那您就是孪河城以南唯一相信我的人
That makes you the only person south of the Twins who does.
我们和孪河城以南的人不一样
We're not like the people south of the Twins.
我们和孪河城以北的人也不一样
And we're not like the people north of the Twins.
在学城  我们为着不同的信仰过着不同的生活
In the Citadel, we lead different lives for different reasons.
我们是世界的记忆  山姆威尔·塔利
We are this world's memory, Samwell Tarly.
没有我们  人将与犬类无异
Without us, men would be little better than dogs.
只记得上一顿饭
Don't remember any meal but the last,
只看得见眼前的事
can't see forward to any but the next.
每次你离开屋子关上门
And every time you leave the house and shut the door,
它们都嚎得好像你再也不回来了
they howl like you're gone forever.
劳勃的叛军横扫大地的时候
When Robert's Rebellion was raging,
人们觉得世界末日到了
people thought the end was near.
坦格利安王朝要结束了  "我们要怎么活"
The end of the Targaryen dynasty. "How will we survive?"
当伊耿·坦格利安的目光转向西方
When Aegon Targaryen turned his eye westward
乘着巨龙飞临黑水河
and flew his dragons to Blackwater Rush,
"世界末日来了  我们要怎么活"
"The end is near! How will we survive?"
几千年前  长夜之时
And thousands of years before that, during the Long Night,
人们有理由相信那真的是末日
we can forgive them for thinking it truly was the end.
但那不是  全都不是
But it wasn't. None of it was.
长城一直屹立不倒
The Wall has stood through it all.
而每一个冬天都结束了
And every winter that ever came has ended.
乖  收拾干净
Be a good lad. Clean this up.
不行
Nope.
你这小子真走运
You're a lucky man.
我听说她单挑打败了猎狗
I've heard she beat the Hound in single combat.
真是个相当厉害的女人
She's a very impressive woman.
你想要什么  贝里席大人
What do you want, Lord Baelish?
我想要你快乐
I want you to be happy.
我想要你安全
I want you to be safe.
我很安全
I am safe.
我在自己家  有朋友陪伴
I'm at home, surrounded by friends.
我有布蕾妮保护  谁也伤不了我
I have Brienne to protect me from anyone who would harm me.
那快乐呢
What about happy?
你为什么不快乐
Why aren't you happy?
你有什么想要却没有的东西
What do you want that you do not have?
此时此刻  安宁和清静
At the moment, peace and quiet.
别费心思总结发言了  贝里席大人
No need to seize the last word, Lord Baelish.
我就当你说了句好听的
I'll assume it was something clever.
小姐
My lady.
告辞
他为什么还在这里
Why is he still here?
我们需要他的军队
We need his men.
要不是谷地支援
Without the Vale,
这座城堡还被拉姆斯·波顿占领着
Ramsay Bolton would still hold this castle.
小指头救了我们
Littlefinger saved us.
他有所欲求
He wants something.
我清楚他的欲求
I know exactly what he wants.
*他奔驰在城里的街道*
*He rode through the streets of the city*
*离开那高高的山岗*
*Down from his hill on high*
*马踏过鹅卵石阶小巷*
*O'er the winds and the steps and the cobbles*
*带他到姑娘的身旁*
*He rode to a woman's sigh*
*她是他珍藏的宝贝呀*
*For she was his secret treasure*
*她是他含羞的期望*
*She was his shame and his bliss*
*项链和城堡都是空呀*
*And a chain and a keep are nothing*
*比不上姑娘的吻好*
*Compared to a woman's kiss*
*金手触摸冰冰凉呀*
*For hands of gold are always cold*
*而姑娘小掌热乎乎*
*But a woman's hands are warm*
*金手触摸冰冰凉呀*
*For hands of gold are always cold*
*而姑娘小掌...*
*But a woman's hands are…*
歌很好听
That's a pretty song.
我没听到过
I've never heard it before.
是首新歌
It's a new one.
你饿了吗  我们有兔子肉
Are you hungry? We've got some rabbit.
我不想偷你们的食物
I don't want to steal your food.
不是偷  是我们给的
You're not stealing, we're offering.
来吧  今晚会很冷
Come on, it's gonna be a cold night.
你要去南方吗
You heading south?
君临
King's Landing.
可怜的姑娘
Poor girl.
没那么糟吧
Not so bad, is it?
取决于你的喜好
Depends on your taste, I guess.
如果你喜欢街上满是
If you like your streets covered
屎尿和猪血  那很适合你
in shit and pig's blood, it's the town for you.
我一直想见到红堡
All my life, I wanted to see the Red Keep,
贝勒大圣堂和龙穴
the Sept of Baelor, the Dragonpit.
等我终于到了君临
Then when I finally make it,
红堡一里之内不得靠近
they wouldn't let me within a mile of the Red Keep,
贝勒大圣堂化为了灰烬
the Sept of Baelor's blown to hell,
而龙穴是一堆七零八落的废墟
and the Dragonpit is a damn ruin.
生活在那里的人
The people who live there,
如果能从你身上搞到两个铜板
they'd skin you alive if
他们会活剥了你
they could make two coppers off your hide.
世上最糟糕的地方
Worst place in the world.
你们在河间地做什么
What are you doing in the Riverlands?
孪河城的佛雷家遇到了麻烦
There's been some trouble with the Freys up at the Twins,
我们是被派去维持治安的一部分军队
so we're part of the army that's been sent to keep the peace.
给  客人优先
Here you go. Guests first.
不  不行  你们不够分
Oh, no, I couldn't. You don't have enough.
我母亲一直教导我要对陌生人友好
My mother always told me to be kind to strangers.
陌生人就会对你友好
Strangers will be kind to you.
你们离家很远
You're a long way from home.
我敢说你们也有些传奇经历
I'm sure you've had some adventures, though.
是的  说不完的传奇
Yeah, endless adventures.
我们的故事将会千年传唱
They'll be singing about us for a thousand years.
事实上  我们离家时迫不及待要走
The truth is when we left home, we couldn't wait to get away.
如今我们出来了  又迫不及待想回家
But now we've been gone a while, we can't wait to get home.
我只是想着我爸独自一人在船上
I just think about my dad out there on his boat all alone.
我应该陪着他的
I ought to be out there with him.
我妻子刚生下我们第一个孩子
My wife just had our first baby.
-男孩还是女孩  -谁知道
- Boy or girl? - Oh, who knows?
你觉得士兵会有信鸦传递家书吗
You think soldiers get ravens with news from home?
-我希望是个女孩  -为什么
- I hope it's a girl. - Why?
女孩会在爸爸年老时照顾他们
Girls take care of their papas when their papas grow old.
男孩只会跑出去替人卖命打仗
Boys just go off to fight in someone else's wars.
你到了喝酒的年纪吗
Are you old enough to drink?
是黑莓酒
It's blackberry wine.
我自己酿的
I made it myself.
很好喝
It's really good.
一个好姑娘孤身一人去君临做什么
So, why is a nice girl on her own heading to King's Landing?
我要去刺杀女王
I'm going to kill the queen.
这天气不适合在外过夜
Bad night to be outdoors.
你可真了不得  竟然能发现这一点
You've got real powerful magic to figure that out.
光之王悄悄告诉你的吗
Did the Lord of Light whisper that in your ear?
"天在下雪  索罗斯  风很大
"It's snowing, Thoros. It's windy.
今晚会很冷"
It's gonna be a cold night."
你是一头暴躁的老狗熊  不是吗  克里冈
You're a grouchy old bear, aren't you, Clegane?
要点朗姆酒吗
You want some rum?
不喜欢那玩意儿  太甜了
Don't like that shit. It's too sweet.
你为什么总是一副臭脾气
Why are you always in such a foul mood?
经历使然
Experience.
在这里过夜好像不错
This seems like a good place to spend the night.
这些人不欢迎我们
These people don't want us here.
好像废弃了  没有牲口
Seems deserted to me. No livestock.
烟囱里没冒烟
No smoke coming from the chimney.
我不喜欢这里的样子
I don't like the look of it.
你这么个彪形大汉  太容易被吓到了
For a big, hard man, you scare easy.
我来告诉你什么吓不到我
I'll tell you what doesn't scare me--
你这样的光头傻蛋
bald cocksuckers like you.
你以为那个顶髻能骗得了所有人吗
You think you're fooling anyone with that top knot?
秃头蠢货
Bald cunt.
来吧
Come on.
没准他们藏了一些麦酒
Maybe they've got some ale hidden away.
他们没有
They don't.
看看有没有地窖
See if there's a larder.
他们总是会留下一些东西
They always leave something behind.
你觉得他们是怎么走的
How do you think it ended for them?
死了
With death.
女孩死在父亲的怀里
Girl died in her father's arms.
他们浑身是血  脚边有一把刀
Both of them covered in blood and a knife at their feet.
我猜他们饿得不行
I'd say they were starving.
他不愿意让小女儿受苦
And rather than let his little girl suffer,
索性结果了两人的性命
he ended it for both of them.
现在不重要了
Doesn't matter now.
是啊  现在不重要了
No, doesn't matter now.
我认识你很久了  唐德利恩
I've known you a long time, Dondarrion.
没错
Aye.
我想我们第一次见面是在比武大会上
I think the first time we met was at that tournament--
我一直觉得你庸俗乏味
And I always thought you were dull as dirt.
你不坏
You're not bad.
我不讨厌你
I don't hate you.
不喜欢你  但你不坏
Don't like you, but you're not bad.
谢谢你  克里冈
Thank you, Clegane.
真暖心
That warms the heart.
但你没什么特别的
But there's nothing special about you.
你说的没错
You're right about that.
那为什么光之王不停地复活你
So why does the Lord of Light keep bringing you back?
我见过比你更好的人
I've met better men than you,
他们被吊死在大梁上  或被砍头
and they've been hanged from crossbeams, or beheaded,
或在荒郊野外惨兮兮地死掉
or just shat themselves to death in a field somewhere.
没一个复活
None of them came back.
你为什么复活
So, why you?
你以为我没自问过
You think I don't ask myself that?
无时不刻
Every hour of every day?
我为何还活着
Why am I here?
我该做什么
What am I supposed to do?
光之王看中了我什么
What does the Lord see in me?
然后呢
And?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不理解我们的神
I don't understand our Lord.
你的神
Your Lord.
我不知道祂要我怎样
I don't know what He wants from me.
我只知道祂希望我活着
I only know that He wants me alive.
既然他无所不能
If he's so all-powerful,
为什么不直接告诉你到底要怎样
why doesn't he just tell you what the fuck he wants?
克里冈
Clegane.
过来
Come over here.
别怕  火又不咬人
Don't worry. The fire won't bite.
我有东西给你看
I want to show you something.
老子掉进崇拜火的人堆里了  真他妈的走运
It's my fucking luck I end up with a band of fire worshippers.
是啊
Aye.
苍天有道
Almost seems like divine justice.
哪有什么道  你个蠢蛋
There's no divine justice, you dumb cunt.
要是真有  你早死了
If there was, you'd be dead...
那个丫头还活着
and that girl would be alive.
-你要干什么  -看着火焰
- What do you want? - Look into the flames.
我才不想看什么该死的火焰
I don't want to look in the damn flames.
你把他砍死后  亲眼看见我把他复活
You saw me bring him back from the dead after you cut him down.
不想知道是什么给了我力量吗
Don't you want to know what gave me the power?
我一直在问  就是没人告诉我
I keep asking and no one wants to tell me.
我们没法告诉你
We can't tell you.
只有火焰能告诉你
Only the fire can tell you.
你看到什么
What do you see?
柴火在烧
Logs burning.
继续看
Keep looking.
你看到什么
What do you see?
冰
Ice.
一堵冰墙
A wall of ice.
是绝境长城
The Wall.
还有什么
What else?
长城与大海相接的地方
It's where the Wall meets the sea.
有一座城堡
There's a castle there.
一座山
There's a mountain.
形状像箭头
Looks like an arrowhead.
死人在行军
The dead are marching past.
成千上万
Thousands of them.
现在相信我了吗  克里冈
Do you believe me now, Clegane?
相信我们是背负使命而来了吗
Do you believe we're here for a reason?
你他妈的在干什么  克里冈
What the hell are you doing, Clegane?
埋葬死者
Burying the dead.
你认识这些人
You knew these people.
算不上
Not really.
天父  请仁慈地评断我等
We ask the Father to judge us with mercy.
圣母  请...
We ask the Mother to...
见鬼  剩下的不记得了
Fuck it, I don't remember the rest.
你们死了我很遗憾
I'm sorry you're dead.
你们不该如此丧命
You deserved better.
两个都是
Both of you.
妈
Mom.
你真的该睡了  山姆
You should really sleep, Sam.
死人可不睡
The dead don't.
《长夜传说》
"Legends of the Long Night."
坦格利安家族使用龙晶装饰武器
The Targaryens used dragonglass to decorate their weapons
甚至不知道先民这样做的目的
without even knowing what the First Men used it for.
这是什么
What is it?
龙石岛的地图
It's a map of Dragonstone.
坦格利安家族入侵维斯特洛时
The Targaryens built their first stronghold there
在那里修建了第一座要塞
when they invaded Westeros.
这是龙晶吗
That's dragonglass?
多得不得了
A mountain of it.
在地底
Beneath the ground.
史坦尼斯告诉过我  但我没想到...
Stannis told me, but I didn't think...
这很重要  一定要告诉琼恩
This is important. Jon needs to know.
她来了吗
Has she come yet?
谁
Who?
龙女王
The Dragon Queen.
风暴降生丹妮莉丝
Daenerys Stormborn.
什么都没听说
Haven't heard anything.
我们开始吧
Shall we begin?
不能相信坦格利安家的人
A Targaryen cannot be trusted.
下集预告
疯王的女儿会摧毁掉王国
The Mad King's daughter will destroy the realm.
我们有一支舰队  还有三头龙
We have an army of fleets and three dragons.
应该即刻攻打君临
We should hit King's Landing now.